Guide to the Elliot W. Eisner Papers SC0878
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elliot W. Eisner papers
1965-1998
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Eisner, Elliot W.
SC0878
118 Linear Feet
Collection pertains to his research and teaching and includes class files, articles, papers, speeches, correspondence, and other materials.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Elliot W. Eisner earned several degrees in art education, culminating in a Ph.D. in Education at the University of Chicago in 1962. He taught at the University of Chicago prior to joining the Stanford University faculty in 1965, becoming professor of education and art in 1970.
Over the course of his academic career, Eisner, the Lee Jacks Professor of Education, Emeritus, at the Stanford Graduate School of Education and professor emeritus of art, championed ways that the arts could benefit student learning, as well as educational practice.
He maintained that the arts are critically important to the development of thinking skills in children and that the arts might offer teachers both a powerful guide and critical tool in their practice. He wrote 17 books and dozens of papers addressing curriculum, aesthetic intelligence, teaching, learning and qualitative measurement, in addition to his frequent and entertaining lectures throughout the nation and abroad.
Eisner's ideas reached beyond academia into the classroom: The National Art Education Association, of which he served as president, turned his list – "10 Lessons the Arts Teach" – into a poster, which can still be found today hanging on school walls nationwide. Among the lessons: The arts teach students that small differences can have large effects; the arts celebrate multiple perspectives; and the arts teach children that in complex forms of problem solving, purposes are seldom fixed but change with circumstance and opportunity.
"To neglect the contribution of the arts in education, either through inadequate time, resources or poorly trained teachers, is to deny children access to one of the most stunning aspects of their culture and one of the most potent means for developing their minds," Eisner wrote.
Eisner eschewed the more popular argument for the arts – that some research showed that instruction in music, dance and painting actually boosted test scores in math and science.
Eisner, rather, talked about art for art's sake.
"He figured out that there was something missing from mainstream educational theory and method," said his friend and Stanford colleague Professor Raymond McDermott. "He wanted to address matters of the heart, whereas most of the discipline was pushing a more mechanical view of the child and the act of teaching or researching."
Eisner reached into areas that sat on the margins of educational discourse: arts education, most literally; the art of education, by extension; and the art of researching education, most controversially, McDermott said.
"He moved these concerns to the front and center," McDermott said.
Eisner's unrelenting advocacy of the arts continued during periods in which arts programs were cut in schools, and a chorus of administrators and policymakers, faced with budget constraints, focused on test scores and worried that spending time painting or drawing was not academic enough.
"One of the casualties of our preoccupation with test scores is the presence – or should I say the absence – of arts in our schools," he wrote in the Los Angeles Times in 2005. "When they do appear they are usually treated as ornamental rather than substantive aspects of our children's school experience. The arts are considered nice but not necessary."
Eisner advocated a strict, more sophisticated and rigorous arts curriculum that would put arts instruction on par with lessons in reading, science and math.
Eisner was born in Chicago on March 10, 1933. From an early age, he was set on pursuing a career as an artist. He graduated in 1954 from Roosevelt University in Chicago with a BA in art and education and the following year received an MS in art education from the Illinois Institute of Technology. He then spent two years as a high school art teacher and discovered that he was more interested in the students than the actual art they were making.
Returning to graduate school in the late 1950s, he received a master's degree and doctorate in education from the University of Chicago. Eisner served as an assistant professor there before joining the Stanford faculty in 1965.
Along with his lectures, writings and teaching, his involvement in such curriculum initiatives as the Kettering Project at Stanford in the late 1960s and the Getty Center for Education in the Arts in the 1980s brought him wide recognition, helping him become an influential voice for teachers, scholars and other educators.
Eisner proposed that the forms of thinking needed to create artistic work were relevant to all aspects of education. Incorporating methods from the arts into teaching of all subjects would cultivate a richer educational experience, he said.
"The arts are fundamental resources through which the world is viewed, meaning is created and the mind developed," he wrote.
His work with the Getty Center advanced what is called Discipline-Based Art Education (DBAE). The curriculum structure advocated in DBAE stresses four aspects of the arts: making it, appreciating it, understanding it and making judgments about it.
This type of arts education, Eisner argued, would result in children better understanding the relationships between culture and art and becoming more artistically literate. He also believed children's conceptions of what knowledge is would be more sophisticated after this type of inquiry.
"His voice for evaluating teaching and student learning through many means, not just standardized testing, continued to be heard during the past three decades of standards-based school reform, testing and accountability," said Larry Cuban, professor emeritus of education at Stanford. "Eisner's eloquence in writing and speech gave heart to and bolstered many educators who felt that the humanities, qualitative approaches to evaluation and artistic criticism had been hijacked by those who wanted only numbers as a sign of effectiveness."
For his achievements, Eisner was honored with the Palmer O. Johnson Memorial Award from the American Educational Research Association, a John Simon Guggenheim Fellowship, a Fulbright Fellowship, the Jose Vasconcelos Award from the World Cultural Council, the Harold W. McGraw Jr. Prize in Education from the McGraw-Hill Research Foundation, the Brock International Prize in Education, the University of Louisville Grawemeyer Award for Education and five honorary degrees. He served as president of the International Society for Education Through Art, the American Educational Research Association and the John Dewey Society. He was a member of the Royal Society of Arts in the United Kingdom, the Royal Norwegian Society of Sciences and Letters and, in the United States, the National Academy of Education.
In addition to his son and daughter, Eisner is survived by his wife of 57 years, Ellie; son-in-law, Eric Eislund; and grandsons Seth and Drew Eislund and Ari Eisner.
Obituary from Stanford News http://news.stanford.edu/news/2014/january/elliot-eisner-obit-011714.html>
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to his research and teaching and includes class files, articles, papers, speeches, correspondence, and other materials.
Art -- Study and teaching.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Faculty; Eisner, Elliot W.; Eisner, Elliot W.
- Papers, Accesion ARCH-2007-245
  - Kettering Project, July, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Study of Children's Art (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Final Report (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mind as Cultural Achievement: The John Dewey Lecture-, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation: Aesthetic Inquiry and The Creation of Meaning: A Program of Instruction For the Elemetnaary School in The Visual Arts (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Seminar in Art Education For Research and Curriculum Development, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Development of Information and Attitude Toward Art At the Secondary And college Levels (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum In the Visual Arts For Elementary School Children (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum In the Visual Arts For Elementary School Children (2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Final Report: The Development of the Concept of Space as Observed in Children's Drawings: A cross-national /Cross-cultural Study (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford University Kettering Project Curriculum in the Visual Arts (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University Kettering Project Curriculum in the Visual Arts(2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum in th Visual Arts for Elementary School Children (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum in th Visual Arts for Elementary School Children (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum in the Visual Arts for Elementary School Children (3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Draft, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Study of Children's Art (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Art Journal & Notes (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The development of Information and Attitudes Toward the Visual Arts at the Secondary and College Levels (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reader: Stanford Colloquim on Museum Education (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Uncertain Profession: Observations on the State of Museum Education in Twenty American Art Museums (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - No Easy Answers: Joseph Schwab's Contri-butions to Curriculum (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Art Education in The Palo Alto Public Schools (1) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Art Education in The Palo Alto Public Schools (2) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Books of The Century Catalog (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Journal of issues and research in art Education (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Various Papers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Pathfinder Publishing Services, 29749 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dialogues on curriculum, 25781 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, January 1991 - August 1991 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, January 1990 - December 1990 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, 1995 - 1996 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, 1994 - 1995 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, Recent Papers, 1994 - 1995 (Box 3)
  - The University of Chicago, The Effect of Noise Distraction Upon Efficiency in Schoolwork, 16990 (Box 3)
  - Art Information For Total Sample and By Sex, Undated (Box 3)
  - The University of Chicago, The Department of Education, 21389 (Box 3)
  - Elliot W. Eisner, School of Education Room 40, Undated (Box 3)
  - What High Schools Are Like: Views From the Inside, 31413 (Box 3)
  - The Uncertain Profession: Observations on the State of Museum Education in Twenty American Art Museums, 31017 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: A - C, March 1969 - June 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: D - F, April 1969 - May 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: G - J, April 1969 - June 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondenc - K - L, Feb 1969 - April 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - M, Feb 1969 - Feb 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: N - R, Feb 1969 - June 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondece: S, Feb 1969 - June 1970 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: T - Z, April 1969 - April 1970 (Box 6)
  - Knowledge, Knowing, and The Visual Arts, Feb 1 - May 1, 1964 (Box 6)
  - O.S.U Course Description Eisner, July 1 - Sept 1, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Letters Received, September - November, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Carbons, May - June, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Letters, May 1 - July 1, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Letters Received, November - December, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, January, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Carbons, November - December, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, April, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, February, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, January - December, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Letters, January - June, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Carbons, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1960 - 1961 (Box 6)
  - Carbons - General, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Letters Received, July 1 - October, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Student Correspondence, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - University, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Letters, September, 1962 - January, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, March, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, February, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, April, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, January, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, December, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, September - October, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, July, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, June, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, May, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, January - February, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, March, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Letters Received, May - June, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Letters Received, March - April, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Carbons, January - February, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Letters, August - September, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Letters Received, January - February, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Letters, October, 1963 - February 1, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Carbons, November - Decembe, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Carbons, September 1 - November 1, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Carbons, July 1 - Sept 1, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Carbons, January - June, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Carbons, July - October, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Carbons, March 15 - May 1, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Carbons, May 1 - July 1, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Letters, November - December, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Carbons, November 1 - March 1, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Carbons, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Letters Received, January, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Letters Received, December, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Letters Received, November, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Letters Received, October, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Letters Received, August, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, July, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, June, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, May, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, June, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, April, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, September, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, August, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, July, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, November, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Carbons, August - September, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Letters, March - April, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, January, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, November, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, October, 1966 (Box 8)
  - December Correpsondence (Box 9A, Folder 1)
  - None (Box 9A, Folder 2)
  - Janurary 1971 (Box 9A, Folder 3)
  - Viktor Lowenfeld Memorial Lecture (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - None (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Instructor (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Eisner Tests-- Art Info Inventory, Art Attit. Invent, Picture Analysis Invent & Manual (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Copyright Material (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Peninsula (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - English Trip- E W Eisner (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Trip to Israel (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Norway Book Project (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - None (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - SUSE Futures Data (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Far West Regional Laboratory (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Pending File (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Kettering- Free School (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Fellowship Applications (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Personal: Travel (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Presentations: E.W. Eisner (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - The Mosswood report- An Appraisal of Oakland's Experimental Art- Centered- School-first 6 months (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Scholarship Awards (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Personal: Professional (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Office of Education #974 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Possible Research Studies in Aut Education (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hanna Specs (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - A proposed Framework for conducting the Search for A New Chairman of the Area of Art Education (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Chapter Referenes from June McFee's Second Edition of Preparation for Art Dec. 1968 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Review Of Educational Research (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Bay Area College Art Educators (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Stanford Study Group (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Art Education - Editorial Board, 1970-75 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Californai Art Educators (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Stanford Art Educators (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Bay Area Art Supervisors (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Research Committee, NAEA (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Com. On Research in Art Education (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Curriculum & Instruction Committee (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - C& I Committee (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Creativitiy Tests (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Transparencies - Tables I-XV (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - C+I Manuscript + Correspondance (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - JDR 3rd Fund: Arts Curric Proj. May 4- NYC (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Stanford University- Personal (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Doctoral Core Requirements-- Art Education, Aug 1967 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Doctoral Core (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - General Curriculum (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Budget- Proctor & Gamble (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - MA requirements-- Elem. & Ec. (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - School of Education Records (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - International Curriculum Training Program, Granna, Sweden (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Mead Corp. (Westab) Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Westab (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Harvard Project Zero (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Art Analysis Inventory (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Applications- Overseas Campuses (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - News Release (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - May, 1966- Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - History of Education Papers (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - ED 200 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Education, 200, Spring 1964 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - ED 321a, Autumn 2002 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - The Analysis of Teaching ED 308 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - ED 308 Analysis of Teaching (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - ED 303, 1997/98 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Education 232b, Fall 1998 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - ED 232b, Fall 1997 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Education 232b- 2001 2002 Fall (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Educortion 232b- Autumn Qtr., 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - ED 219 Materials, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - ED 2190 Autumn 1999 Artisitic Development of the Child (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Ed 200x Winter 99-00 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Education 200 Winter '02-'3 M/W 1:15-3:05 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Disadvataged No. 2 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Audiovisual material
    - Eisner pt. 1 How Children Express What is on Their Minds (Box 5)
    - Eisner pt. 2 How Children Express What is on Their Minds (Box 5)
    - Eisner Autobiographical Lecture in Art Education - Miami University, 3/7/1996; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
    - Curr. Orientations at UCSC Ed. 340- Dr. Elliott Esiner, 12/8/1975; 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 5)
    - Eisner #2, 2/9/1976; 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 5)
    - Eisner #2, 2/26/1976; 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 5)
    - Eisner, 3/10/1976; 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 5)
    - Elliot Eisner Discussion #2, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 5)
    - Impression and Expression in Artistic Development by Harry Broudy, University of Illinois, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Goals and Roles in the Art Educatin of Children, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - The Critical Act in Aesthetic Inquiry by David Ecker (New York University), 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - The Unseeing Eye: Critical Consciousness and The Teaching of Art, 4/23/1973; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - "Robin Alexander Tape #1, Art History: Conceptual Approach, Critique: Raggedy Anns and Teddy, Demonstration: Charcoal and Chalk", 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Ceredo- Kumone Jr. H.S., 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Dorothy Blackmore, Early Childhood Education: Where are we Now?, 2/2/1976; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Educating Both Sides of the Brain by Elliot Eisner, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Eisner, 2/9/1976; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Disclosure of Classroom Life, Gail McClutchon, 1976; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Elliot Eisner Lecture #2, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - Marta Fulop CASBS Interview #1, 11/20/1997; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Marta Fulop CASBS Interview #2, 12/2/1997; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Marta Fulop CASBS Interview #3, 1/20/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Marta Fulop CASBS Interview #4, 1/27/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Foster, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Arthur Hall- Paper Critique, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Adrian Hoffman, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Oscar Leme, 3/26/2003; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Andy Disessa Interview CASBS #1, 3/19/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Andy Disessa Interview CASBS #2, 3/26/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Oscar STGRA-01, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Jerry Reaven STGRA- 05, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Roz STGRA- 06, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Hank Jones STGRA- 02 & STGRA- 04, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Linda Derling Hammond CASBS interview #1, 2/13/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Linda Derling Hammond CASBS interview #2, 3/26/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Istvan Ren CASBS Interview #1, 1/22/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Istvan Ren CASBS Interview #2, 1/28/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Print Interview Conducted with Lisa and Teresa, 10/25/1996; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Charles Matthew, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Blaise Degionger, 10/14/2003; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Mary Francis Callen STGRA- 08, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Janice Ross STGRA- 09, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Interview with Kirsten Keith, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - English Evaluations: Usis Doblin & Elliot Eisner on Curriculum Part 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Keit Bartel, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - The Arts and Education by Elliot Eisner, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Describing and Defining Art Education by June King McFee, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Quality Education and the Arts by Laura Chapman, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Art in the Mainstream by Edmund b. Feldman, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - The Importance of the Arts for Children by Lambert Brittain, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5A)
    - Dr. John Tutino, August 12 & 13 [no year noted], 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - H.A.I.S. Pacific Basin Conference, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - "Our Science Lab" "Gerirtz Academic Summer Progam", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - Sandra Harding, Sch. Of Ed. lecture [inside label says Elliot Wisner 3/23/95], 1993 Oct 6; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - Inter Prin Center's Conversation Keynote Speeches, May 1994; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - "Under Siege" San Francisco, 4/22/95; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - KLRN Artbeat "Learning with Artists", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - Refugee Children & Their Art in Times of War (Zabreb, Croatia; E. R. Tanay, Professor), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - Nurturing the Spirit of Dance. Keith Jones productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 9)
    - "Meaningful Integration of Art in a School Program," Viktor Lowenfeld, University of Kansas, 1960 Feb 27; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Cubberley Curriculum Conference #2 (Begle, Schriven, MacDonald, Schutz), 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Hilda Lewis, "Forecasting, Crystal Gazing, and Wishful thinking: The Future of the Arts in Education," 4/28/75, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Herbert Read, Symposium, UC Berkeley; intro. By James Jarrett., 1965; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Brian Sutton-Smith "Initial Education as Caricature" ED 461, Winter 1979; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Public Lecture Series – Robert Stake, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Public Lecture Series – Anne Taylor, 1977; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Related Arts Lecture Series – Dr. Gerald Kneiter, 1977; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)